Varun Dani

Profile

Full stack developer with **4** years of experience in designing and implementing software applications and frameworks working with an agile team, well versed in managing team members and also to be a team player to ensure timely completion of all deadlines.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology Atlanta, GA. M.S., Computer Science (4.0) Expected Dec 2018
The University of Texas at Dallas Richardson, TX. M.S., Computer Science 2016 – 2017
Ganpat University, Gujarat, India B. Tech., Information Technology 2008 – 2012

Work Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug 2017 - Present

College of Computing, Georgia Institute of Technology

- Assist/grade Graduate students for Subject - Software Development Process.

Software Engineering Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Copart Inc. Dallas, Texas

- Development of software component in AngularJS, Typescript, Java, Spring Boot.
- Deliver new version of Product by planned Sprints in Agile environment.
- Effectively communication with Business and DevOps Team for product delivery.

Senior Software Engineer (ITA)

Sep 2012 - July 2016

TATA Consultancy Services, India

- Key member of Framework Team for Taxation Projects and Module Lead for Registration & Payment modules for one of the Taxation Projects.
- Working with framework team to develop various components of TCS's taxation framework using technologies like J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, OpenLDAP, Alfresco.
- Lead for the customized Dashboard framework (\$250K+ contribution in revenue):
 Reports can be custom generated from materialized View (or JSON) and configured in terms of columns, parameters, and filters after customization of Data Tables.
- Implemented Near Site and Far Site structure for fetching transactional/report Data
- -Lead for Client-Side Utility project: JavaFX desktop application that works offline and synchronize on internet connection.

Software Engineering Intern

Dec 2011 - Apr 2012

TATA Consultancy Services, India

- Developer and team member for projects that involves integrated work flow system.
- Developed web components in Java and ZK framework.

Projects

• Domestic Taxation Framework Project

- Framework used by **5+** states of India for collecting Indirect Taxes from **10M+** citizens.
- Framework serve 15000+ http calls per hour.
- Architect, Design, and Development of Framework including various components in J2EE, Spring, Hibernate.

YouTube 8M Challenge (Kaggle Competition) (TensorFlow)

- Machine learning team project for analysing and classification of YouTube videos.
- Used Google cloud Machine Learning engine to achieve GAP value 0.7036

• Al Agent to Solve Raven's Progressive Matrices.

- Al agent that implements cognitive methodologies and semantic nets to solve RPM.

Let's Teach

- Android Mobile Application to Connect Learners to volunteers.
- Includes Google App Engine, Cloud Functions and Firebase with dialogFlow support that enables access from Amazon Alexa, Google Home, Skype, Slack, LINE, Web.

https://varundani.github.io/
in www.linkedin.com/in/varun-dani

Area of Expertise -

Programming: Java, J2EE, JavaFX, Python, Android, C, SQL, PL-SQL.

Frameworks: Hibernate, Spring, Jersey(RESTful), SOAP, JCS, jBPM, ZK.

Web: Angular JS, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, XML Schema (XSD), AJAX, JSON, REST API, Bootstrap-css

Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle9i, Mongo DB

Other: Apache Tomcat, JBoss AS7, Apache Solr, ElasticSearch, Apache Kafka, and Agile (SCRUM).

Certifications -

- "R" For Data Scientists UT Dallas
- Big Data Technologies Hadoop,
 Pig, Hive UT Dallas.
- Advance Java [J2EE] Certification.

Achievements -

- "Google Developer Challenge Scholarship" 2018 Recipient.
- Honorary Mentions: Convergence Innovation Competition, Fall-2017.
- Award Winner: "Technical Excellence", for cohesive architecture building of framework.
- Award Winner: "Best Practice", as Lead of customized Dashboard Framework.
- Valedictorian honor Ganpat University.

Courses -

- Knowledge Based Artificial Intelligence
- Computational Creativity
- Software Mining
- Machine Learning
- Design and Analysis of Algorithms
- Object Oriented Software Engineering
- Mobile Applications and Services
- Network Security

Leadership -

- Career Fair Volunteer: Georgia Tech
- Engineers Week Volunteer: UT Dallas
- Food4Life Atlanta Volunteer